<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bangalore Metro on FunderfulWorld</title>
    <link>http://funderfulworld.com/tags/bangalore-metro/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bangalore Metro on FunderfulWorld</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2017 [FunderfulWorld](http://funderfulworld.com). Powered by [Hugo](//gohugo.io). Original theme by [Colorlib](http://colorlib.com/wp/travelify/) adapted for Hugo by [Dr. Bala Ramadurai](http://balaramadurai.net).</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://funderfulworld.com/tags/bangalore-metro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Metro Mania</title>
      <link>http://funderfulworld.com/thetravelbug/metro-mania/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 09:15:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://funderfulworld.com/thetravelbug/metro-mania/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  Our long wait ended in November 2011. We boarded &lt;a title=&#34;Bangalore Metro Rail Corporation Limited&#34; href=&#34;http://bmrc.co.in/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Namma Metro&lt;/a&gt;, which had recently commenced operations in Namma Bengaluru! 🙂 And in style! The metro ride is now a weekly affair for us. A must-do on most Sunday mornings. It&amp;#8217;s a fun way to spend a couple of hours and keep a toddler completely entertained. One line, about 6 km, 12 min. Too short? Yeah, we agree. Sooner (or later ;)) we hope to see the other reaches complete. Our routine: Hop on at Byappanahalli, cruise through Indira Nagar and Ulsoor, and then hop off at MG Road. A cuppa chai (or even lunch, depending on the time) and a bookstore visit later, it is time for the ride home.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  MG Road used to be a &amp;#8216;worrisome&amp;#8217; destination for us due to the parking concerns. Auto rides were always a hassle. The Metro has completely eliminated our troubles.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  Our FAVORITE way to explore a city is via metro. Travel by foot follows a close second :).
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  Our fascination with this mode of transport began in Delhi. We spent an entire afternoon riding along the 2 lines that existed in the capital at that time. The network has greatly expanded since then, and we&amp;#8217;d love to experience the trains in the capital again.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  The unique charm of each station and the amazing connectivity push the Paris Metro to the top of my list of favorites. The wonderful rides when we &lt;a title=&#34;The Vibrance of Barcelona, in pictures – I&#34; href=&#34;http://funderfulworld.com/older-travel-tales-2010-and-earlier/the-vibrance-of-barcelona-in-pictures/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;explored vibrant Barcelona&lt;/a&gt;, the excitement in the Metropolitana at Rome (where any underground digging runs the risk of ruining a &amp;#8216;ruin&amp;#8217;! ), and the couple of times we took the Metro at Marseille are unforgettable.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  We couldn&amp;#8217;t resist the metro journeys in Beijing and Shanghai. At the ticket counter, our earnest efforts to correctly pronounce the destination names earned us several appreciative smiles. &lt;a title=&#34;Postcards from Bangkok: A Great Stopover Destination&#34; href=&#34;http://funderfulworld.com/older-travel-tales-2010-and-earlier/postcards-from-bangkok-a-great-stopover-destination/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A brief stopover in Bangkok&lt;/a&gt; allowed us to experience the MRT in the city. The Dubai Metro offered stunning views of the glitzy and glamourous edifices along Sheikh Zayed Road during a &lt;a title=&#34;Escape to Dubai – I&#34; href=&#34;http://funderfulworld.com/thetravelbug/escape-to-dubai/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;wonderful vacation&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  Saint Petersburg, London, Buenos Aires, Santiago, Hong Kong, Tokyo, and Kolkata (much closer home!) have found a place on our &amp;#8216;Metro wishlist&amp;#8217;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  Here&amp;#8217;s a list of the &lt;a title=&#34;Ten Top Metros of the World&#34; href=&#34;http://www.businesstraveller.com/archive/2012/march-2012/special-reports/ten-top-metros-of-the-world&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ten top metros of the world&lt;/a&gt;, published by Business Traveller.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: left;&#34;&gt;
  Do you like to take the Metro? Which one is your favorite?
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>